我们需要谈谈
We have a lot to talk about.
《行尸走肉》
你袭击了我们
You attacked us.
分明是跟我们作对
Makes things pretty clear.
难道你还不明白吗
I was trying to make things clear.
我本可以把你们全杀光  但我没有
I could have killed you all. I didn't.
现在总算见面了
And here we are.
我准备卸下枪
I'm gonna remove my weapon.
以表明我谈判的诚意
Show that I mean to negotiate in good faith.
我希望你也如此
I'd like you to do the same.
可以吗
May I?
看吧
See?
我无恶意
No trouble.
轮到你了
Now you.
那么...
Well...
随你便吧
suit yourself.
他已经进去了
He's already in there.
在和瑞克谈判
Sat down with Rick.
没看见有车
I don't see any cars.
感觉不太对劲
It don't feel right.
别熄火
Keep it running.
来人了
Heads up.
搞什么名堂  你们的人怎么早就进去了
What the hell? Why's your boy already in there?
-他到了吗  -没错
- He's here? - Yup.
什么情况
What's going on?
没什么
Nothing.
你的朋友没诚意
Your friend isn't much for small talk.
你想谈  那就快谈
You want to talk, talk.
是我想让你们谈
I wanted you to talk.
已经有太多人白白丧命了
Too many people have died for no reason.
必须做个了结
Let's end this.
不要无谓争斗  浪费子弹了
Save the bullets for the real threat.
我们能改变现状
We can solve this.
所以我才找你们来这儿
That's why I asked you to come here.
我知道你的那些勾当
I know what you've done.
袭击他人  人头鱼缸
I heard about the raids, the heads,
-还有玛姬  -那是莫尔做的
- Maggie. - Merle did that.
不  你知道我说的是什么
No. You know what I'm talking about.
你了解我  我也了解你
You know all about me and I know all about you.
这些都无所谓
I don't care about any of that.
关键是向前看
We're here to move forward.
或许我该进去看看
Maybe I should go inside.
总督希望和瑞克单独谈判
The Governor thought it best if he and Rick spoke privately.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
米尔顿·马梅特
Milton Mamet.
不错嘛  还带着管家
Great. He brought his butler.
我是他的顾问
I'm his advisor.
顾哪门子的问
What kind of advice?
做计划  研究行尸
Planning. Biters.
不好意思
Uh, you know, I'm sorry.
我没必要向别人马仔解释
I don't feel like I need to explain myself to the henchmen.
小子  说话注意点
You better watch your mouth, sunshine.
如果我们一整天
Look, if you and I are gonna be out here
都要端着枪  守在这儿
pointing guns at each other all day,
行行好吧  闭上臭嘴
do me a favor, shut your mouth.
没必要动粗  如果里面出事了
We don't need this. If all goes south in there,
我们也得拼个你死我活
we'll be at each other's throats soon enough.
卡尔  过来
Carl, come here.
你把这些藏到装卸区  好吗
You stash these at the loading dock. All right?
贝丝  通道那再多放一些
Beth, put more up on the catwalk.
如果有人被困住了
If anyone gets pinned down,
得确保他们有足够弹药
we need to make sure that they have plenty of ammo.
我去外面的牢笼守着
I'll go work on the cage outside.
我们应该做的是开上车
What we should be doing is loading some of this firepower
装上武器  拜访总督
in a truck and paying a visit to the Governor.
我们知道他现在在哪
We know where he is right now.
你的意思是我们直接进去杀了他吗
Are you suggesting that we just go in and kill him?
对  没错
Yeah, I am.
我们告诉瑞克和达里尔我们会待在这
We told Rick and Daryl that we'd stay put.
我改主意了  宝贝
I've changed my mind, sweetheart.
让我弟弟自己出去
Being on the sideline with my brother out there
我却待在这里无所事事
ain't sitting right with me.
他们三个正在那里谈判
The three of them are right in the middle of it.
对我们的到来毫无准备
No idea we're coming.
他们可能会被扣为人质或者杀死
They could get taken hostage or killed.
后果不堪设想
A thousand things could go wrong.
我们不去他们也会的
And they will.
我爸爸能照顾好自己
My dad can take care of himself.
抱歉  孩子  但是你爸爸
Sorry, son, but your dad's head
没准一会就人头分家了
could be on a pike real soon.
别对他说那种话
Don't say that to him.
这个办法行不通
It's not the right move.
起码现在不行
Not now.
不能让他们置身交叉火力之中
Can't take the risk of putting them in the crossfire.
我已下决定  不要再说了
That's my decision. It's final.
我在不同的时间认识了你们两个
I've known you both at different times,
但都是在这个世界变得一团混乱之后
but only after the world went to shit.
你们两个都冒着很大的人身危险
And you both stepped up for the good of others
为他人造福
at great personal risk.
-没有理由...  -有话直说
- There's no reason-- - Get to it.
河西归伍德伯里所有
Woodbury takes west of the river.
河东归监狱
The prison takes east.
互不干扰  互不交涉
No one crosses, no one trades.
他说得对
He's right.
我们应该划清边界线  互不相扰
We should hammer out boundaries, then leave each other--
-不好意思  这是什么  -解决方案
- I'm sorry, what is this? - It's a solution.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
那我来这做什么  你告诉我
What the hell am I doing here? You told me--
-你告诉他什么  -你告诉我他想协商
- Told him what? - You told me he was willing to talk.
没错  但是事实上  瑞克
I am, but the truth is, Rick,
这事可不是她说了算
she's in no position to make such an offer anyway.
我今天来只为了一件事
I'm here for one thing only--
你们的投降
your surrender.
你想要投降  放马过来吧
Oh, you want surrender? Come get it.
我们上次打得伍德伯里还不够惨吗
You think we hit Woodbury heavy last time?
别着急好吗  我们是来解决问题的
Just take it easy, all right? We're here to settle this.
你说得对  你出去一下好吗
You're right. Would you step outside?
什么
What?
我和瑞克有很多话要说
Rick and I, we got a lot to talk about.
-我不会出去的  -我是来和他谈判的
- I'm not leaving. - I came to talk to him.
你就是总督
So you're the Governor.
那是他们的叫法  不是我自己起的
That's-- that's their term, not mine.
但是
But still,
你还是要对你的人负责
you're beholden to your people.
-当然了  -你对他们有责任
- Well, of course. - You have responsibility to them.
莫尔不是你的副手吗
Wasn't Merle your lieutenant?
他对我们很有帮助
He was helpful, yeah.
但你知道他很暴戾
But you knew he was erratic.
你怪他不该
You blame him
绑走格伦和玛姬吗
for scooping up Glenn and Maggie in the first place?
是的  当你袭击我们的时候
Exactly. I was trying to sort it out
我正想解决此事
when you attacked.
所以是他的错了
So it was his fault?
他很不好管  但是他办事效率高
He's a wild card, but he's effective.
他能做好脏活
He gets the dirty jobs done.
我还以为你会承担这个责任呢
I thought you'd take responsibility.
我还以为你是个警察  不是善辩的律师
I thought you were a cop, not a lawyer.
不管怎样  我不会去扮什么总督
Either way, I don't pretend to be a governor.
我说过  我是他们的领导者
I told you, I'm their leader.
你就是个推倒我的栅栏
You're the town drunk
毁坏我院子的混账
who knocked over my fence and ripped up my yard,
仅此而已
nothing more.
你曾经看错过人吗
Didn't you ever misjudge someone?
安德莉亚跟我说了你的孩子
Andrea told me about your baby.
有可能是你搭档的种
That it might be your partner's.
但是你愿抚养她  我很钦佩
But you're caring for her and I admire that.
是你缺乏洞察力的见证
Restitution for your own lack of insight.
没有看清你身边的恶魔
For failing to see the devil beside you.
我能看清谁是恶魔
Oh, I see him, all right.
我带了威士忌
I brought whiskey.
没有理由不利用一下现在的时间
There's no reason not to use this time we have together
来谈谈我们的问题
to explore the issues ourselves.
老大说坐下把嘴闭上
Boss said to sit tight and shut up.
怎么不叫总督大人
Don't you mean the Governor?
他们坐下谈是件好事
It's a good thing they're sitting down,
尤其是在不幸发生后
especially after what happened.
他们会解决的  没人想再发动战争了
They're gonna work it out. Nobody wants another battle.
我不会管这个叫战争的
I wouldn't exactly call it a battle.
我会的  我刚叫完
I would call it a battle and I did.
我还记录下来了
I recorded it.
为什么
For what?
总要有人记录下来我们所经历的事
Somebody's got to keep a record of what we've gone through.
会成为历史的一部分
It'll be a part of our history.
有道理
That makes sense.
我采访了很多
I've got dozens of interviews--
你先请
After you.
没门  你先
No way. You first.
娘炮
Pussy.
看看这是什么
Look what he's got.
我喜欢抽薄荷醇的
Nah, I prefer menthols.
傻帽
Douchebag.
你是军人吗
You army or something?
不是  我就是
Nah, I just--
恨这些行尸
just hate these things.
他们伤害了我的
After what they did to
妻子和孩子
my wife, kids.
太糟了
Sucks.
谢了
Thanks.
这不过是逢场作戏  对吧
This is a joke, right?
他们什么都解决不了
They ain't gonna work anything out.
没错  他们会做做样子
Sure, they'll do their little dance
然后明天  后天
and tomorrow, next day...
他们就会下令开战
they'll give the word.
我知道
I know.
介意我问问你是怎么失去一条腿的吗
May I ask how you lost your leg?
我被咬了
I was bit.
为了防止感染扩散
So you cut off your leg
你砍下了自己被咬的那条腿吗
to keep the infection from spreading?
很有意思
Interesting.
你是在被咬后的多长时间内砍的
How long after the initial bite?
立刻
Immediately.
你没有失血过多吗
You didn't bleed out?
当时有一些懂医术的人
We have good people.
他们悉心照料我
They took care of me.
是医生吗
Doctors?
不是
No.
我们靠实践摸索出来的
We learned by trial and error.
我也是
Me, too.
我能看一下吗
May I see it?
你的假肢  我想要
Your stump. I'd like to, um...
我想看一下你采取的截肢术是怎样的
ahem, see where the amputation was.
离被咬的伤口有多远的距离
How high above the bite.
我才不给你看我的腿
I'm not showing you my leg.
这是一项重要的数据
It's important data.
我才刚刚认识你
I just met you.
你至少得先给我买杯酒
At least buy me a drink first.
我关心我的同伴们
I care about my people
我从来没有轻视他们的生命
and I don't take their deaths lightly,
我知道你和我一样
and I know you don't either.
在某种程度上  这场战斗
In a way, this fight,
是我们领导的败笔
it's a failure of leadership.
那就别骚扰我们了
Then leave us alone.
现在停手  那就是更大的失败
Well, now, that would be an even bigger failure.
你进驻我们的后院
You've moved into our backyard.
在我们的街道上扫射
You shot up Main Street.
如果我对这威胁置之不理  会显得我很弱
If I let that threat persist, I look weak
然后  领导结构就会崩塌
and, well, the whole thing crumbles.
那是你的问题  你的选择
Well, that's your problem. Your choice.
这不正是我们来此的目的吗
Now, isn't that why we're here?
作出选择
Choice.
如果我们选择毁灭
If we choose to destroy
一切过去奋斗的成果都将幻灭
everything we've fought for over the past year...
我们会害死我们认识的所有人
we're gonna kill everyone we know.
监狱的人
At your prison.
伍德伯里的人
Back in Woodbury.
我们所爱的人  瑞克
People we love, Rick.
有一天  我正在
I was at work one day
听一个岁数只有我一半大的上司讲鬼话
taking shit from a boss half my age
那小子的智商堪忧
and an IQ even lower.
然后电话响了起来
And the phone rang.
我妻子出了意外
My wife had been in an accident.
"抱歉  布莱克先生  我们已竭尽所能了"
"Sorry, Mr. Blake, we did everything we could."
我就呆呆地坐在那里  手握电话
I sat there holding that phone,
心里清楚我再也见不到她了
knowing that I would never see her again.
她死了
Gone.
只是场意外  不是谁的错
It was just an accident. No one's fault.
她给我留了封语音邮件让我回电话
She had left a voice-mail asking me to call her,
但我当时没有机会了
but I hadn't had a chance yet.
我坐在那儿  拿着电话想...
I sat there clutching that phone thinking,
"她想干什么"
"What did she want?"
报个平安吗
Just to check in?
让我顺道买晚饭吗
Ask me to pick something up for dinner?
她到底想干什么
What did she want?
你不准离开
Hey, you're not going.
我不需要批准
I don't need permission.
-我不能让你走  -你拦不了我
- I can't let you. - You can't stop me.
你要想和我们住一起
If you're gonna live here with us,
就要守我们的规矩
it's gonna be on our terms.
如果米琼恩能做到  你怎么就不能
If Michonne can do it, why can't you?
因为外面那是我弟弟  这就是原因
'Cause it's my brother out there, that's why.
你们到底发什么病啊
What's the matter with y'all?
我不会让你置他们于危险中的
I'm not gonna let you put them in danger.
有点种吧
Nut up already, boy.
那个人渣吃你女人的豆腐
This guy cops a feel of your woman
而你就这样认怂吗
and you pussy out like this?
别挡我的路
Get out of my way.
不
No.
给我滚开
Get out of my way!
起来
Get up!
放开我  放开我
Let me go! Let me go!
失陪一会儿
If you'll excuse me.
你在那边怎么样
How's it going in there?
他们排挤我
They kicked me out.
我不知道自己在这儿干什么
I don't know what I'm doing here.
你是想帮忙啊
You're trying to help.
玛姬出了什么事
What happened with Maggie?
他是个变态
He's a sick man.
我现在该怎么做
What am I gonna do now?
我不能回去
I can't go back there.
我们是一家人  你应该和我们在一起
We're family. You belong with us.
但是如果你回来
But if you join us,
就不能反悔
it's settled.
我知道
I know.
其实  我一点也不想当老大
You know, the truth is I didn't want any of this.
他们选择了我  因为没有更好的人选
They chose me because there was nobody else around.
他们仍然认为
And they still think that I'm the man
我是能保证他们安全的人
that can keep them safe.
他们仍然认为我知道自己在做什么
They still think I know what I'm doing.
我知道你们枪不少
I know you got guns.
你那天带回来不少家伙
Mmm. That was quite a stash you brought back the other day.
我的人不像你的人有丰富的作战经验
Now, my people, they're not combat-tested like yours are,
但我的手下人数众多
but I've got more of them.
这场战斗会一直继续  直到一方俱灭
So this fight, it will go down to the last man.
我们做个了结吧
So let's end it.
就今天
Today.
我们别这样
Let's not do this.
我们可以停止战斗
We can walk away.
你有我想要的
You have something
某件东西
that I want.
这件东西能让所有不快烟消云散
One thing that makes this all all right.
我不会把监狱拱手相让
I'm not giving up the prison.
不
No.
不  我
No, I--
我不想要你的监狱  那里不安全
I don't want your prison. That doesn't sound safe at all.
你在那里失去了你妻子  同伴
I mean, you lost your wife, another man.
我们不会离开
We're not moving on.
那对我来说更好
What good would that do me?
刚好我能用独眼监视你们
Best you stay where I can keep my one good eye on you.
我要米琼恩
I want Michonne.
交她出来  既往不咎
Turn her over and this all goes away.
很超值吧
Is she worth it?
一个女人
One woman...
换一监狱的人命
worth all those lives at your prison?
不是吗
Is she?
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
这里的人
The folks here,
他们很坚强
they're strong,
会战斗
good fighters.
但他们不会杀人
But they ain't killers.
瑞克杀过
Rick is.
玛姬杀过
Maggie is.
卡尔杀了自己母亲
Carl put down his own mother.
那叫解脱痛苦
Mercy killing.
跟杀人可不一样
That don't make him an assassin.
但你会
Mmm, but you are.
不得已时我会
When I have to be.
那你怎么解释没杀掉我
Then how do you explain letting me get away?
我一定是被你的
I must have been seduced
人格魅力迷惑了
by your sterling personality.
你跟不跟我去
You coming with me or not?
我和我弟弟  我们打猎时有一些暗号
Me and my brother, we have a few calls we use when we hunt.
我会提前告知他
I'll give him a heads up.
他能提醒自己人
He'll warn the others.
你去把总督斩了
You shogun the Governor's ass,
我解决其他人
I'll take care of the rest.
一眨眼就能搞定
We'll be home before you know it.
安德莉亚怎么办
And what about Andrea?
子弹横飞时  她必须迅速做出选择
Bullets fly, she's gonna have to make her choice real quick.
你还是自己去吧
You're on your own.
谁被害死  都是你的责任
You get people killed, it's on you.
我以为轮我值班了
I thought it was my watch.
我来吧
I got it.
陪陪你
Keep you company?
我差点没被掐死
That was a hell of a choke hold.
我应该直接干掉他
I should have put him to sleep.
我们从伍德伯里回来后
When we got back from Woodbury...
我光顾着自己
I made it all about me.
你需要空间  我却咄咄逼人
And you needed your space and I didn't give you that.
我们之间不需要空间
I didn't need my space from you.
我只是想让你知道
I just... wanted you to see me.
我就在你眼前
I'm with you.
我伴你左右
I'm always with you,
我永伴你左右
you know?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道
I know.
-对不起  -我知道
- I'm sorry. - I know.
我爱死你了
Oh, God, I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
-等一下  -怎么
- Wait. - Hmm?
我不要在这里
I can't do this.
来  到这边来  来这里
Come here. Come here. Come here.
-哎呦  -我没事
<i>' 0w!</i>
我搞不明白
Yeah, I don't get it.
很明显  你胸怀大志
You've obviously got big plans.
你就像是那种不计前嫌
Like you're the guy who's gonna lick this thing.
拯救我们于危难之中
Bring us back from the brink.
为何把时间浪费在这样微不足道的仇杀上
So why waste your time on a two-bit vendetta?
为何冒这么大风险
Why risk it all?
人们甚至愿意在小镇广场
You could have a statue of yourself
为你树立雕像  总督大人
in the town square, Governor.
杀死米琼恩
Killing Michonne
不太像你会做的事  你不这么认为吗
is sort of beneath you, don't you think?
你能救你儿子
You could save your son.
还能救你的女儿
Save your daughter.
所有你认识的人
Everyone you know.
选择权在你
It's your choice.
如果我把米琼恩交给你
If I give you Michonne,
我怎么知道你不会食言
how do I know you'll keep your word
就此善罢甘休呢
that you'll stop?
你可以得到你需要的一切
You can have everything you want.
我对你说过  我不在乎你
I told you, I don't care about you.
你考虑考虑吧
You think about it.
两天时间
Two days.
我正午时分来这里
I'll be here at noon.
大家都进去
Let's get inside.
在那家农资店四周埋伏好枪手
Position gunmen all around that feed store.
一旦你见到米琼恩  马上开火
The minute you see Michonne, you open fire.
留她活口  把其他人都干掉
Kill the others, but you keep her alive.
那定的协议呢
What about the deal?
瑞克  莫尔的弟弟都会来
Well, they'll bring Rick, Merle's brother,
或许还有格伦和莫尔
maybe Glenn, Merle himself.
我们能把这帮人都干掉
We can take care of the whole crew.
这是避免发生屠杀的最佳方案
It's the best way to avoid a slaughter.
这本身就是屠杀
That is a slaughter.
对我们来说不是
Not at our end.
我们早晚得灭了瑞克
We're gonna have to eliminate Rick sooner or later.
比邻共存是不可能的
No way we can all live side by side.
谢谢你组织了这次谈判
Thanks for setting that up.
你真的是不辞辛苦啊
You really put yourself out there.
我很开心能帮上忙
Glad I could help.
我和瑞克定了条件
Rick and I set terms.
他回去考虑一下
He's gonna consider them
两天后我们再见面
and then we'll meet again in two days.
是什么样的条件
What sort of terms?
希望能谈妥
Hope it works out.
我和总督会面了
So, I met this Governor.
跟他谈了好一会儿
Sat with him for quite a while.
就你们两个吗
Just the two of you?
对
Yeah.
我说我们该去吧  老兄
Should have gone when we had the chance, bro.
他想要监狱
He wants the prison.
他想要我们消失
He wants us gone.
死
Dead.
他想我们死
He wants us dead
因为我们毁了伍德伯里
for what we did to Woodbury.
我们要开战了
We're going to war.
大家的反应是预料之中的镇定啊
The group's taking it as well as can be expected.
莫尔和米琼恩认为
Merle and Michonne are convinced
我们该先发制人
we should hit first.
我和卡萝尔认为我们应该逃跑
Carol and I think we should take our chances on the road.
可咱们是一家人
We're in this together.
所以  如果大家要留下战斗
So if we stay and fight,
那就这么定了
so be it.
他给了我另一个选择
He gave me a choice.
一条生路
A way out.
他有什么条件
What does he want?
他要米琼恩
Michonne.
他会杀掉她
He'll kill her.
然后会照样杀掉我们
And then kill us anyway.
万一他不这么做呢
But what if he doesn't?
万一他真的放我们走呢
What if this is the answer?
你为什么不告诉他们
Why didn't you tell them?
他们需要
They need
感到害怕
to be scared.
他们确实害怕
They are.
那就好
Good.
只有害怕他们才会接受这条件
'Cause that's the only way they'll accept it.
她救过我的命
She saved my life.
也救过卡尔
And Carl's.
格兰  玛姬
Glenn, Maggie--
如果她没过来
if she hadn't come here,
我们根本不会知道他们被抓了
we never would have known they were taken.
她赢得了一席之地
She's earned her place.
是啊
Yeah.
说的没错
Yeah, she has.
你愿意牺牲自己女儿来保护她吗
Are you willing to sacrifice your daughters' lives for her?
你为什么要告诉我
Why are you telling me?
因为
Because...
我希望你能劝我别那样做
I'm hoping you can talk me out of it.